<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Site on The personal website of Jon Saville</title><link>https://jonsaville.com/tags/site/</link><description>Recent content in Site on The personal website of Jon Saville</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jonsaville.com/tags/site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Happy New Year 2025</title><link>https://jonsaville.com/post/2025/01/happy-new-year-2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonsaville.com/post/2025/01/happy-new-year-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year, another post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2024 was a big year for my family - my sister got married, my parents downsized from the house I grew up in, and I turned 50 during a holiday in the Scottish Highlands. That holiday coincided with the solar storm in May, and we were treated to a spectacular aurora display in spectacular surroundings. 2025 promises to be just as busy.&lt;/p>






























































&lt;a class="galleryImage" href="#image0">
 &lt;figure class=" copyright" id="#inlineimage0">
 &lt;img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset='
 
 /post/2025/01/happy-new-year-2025/ScotlandAurora_hu13090554001127356788.jpg 500w
 
 
 , /post/2025/01/happy-new-year-2025/ScotlandAurora_hu11169092596345402443.jpg 800w
 
 
 , /post/2025/01/happy-new-year-2025/ScotlandAurora_hu9362880832953753794.jpg 1200w
 
 
 , /post/2025/01/happy-new-year-2025/ScotlandAurora_hu5125750263471072906.jpg 1500w 
 ' src="https://jonsaville.com/post/2025/01/happy-new-year-2025/ScotlandAurora.jpg" alt="Aurora over the Highlands of Scotland, May 2024">
 &lt;figcaption>
 Aurora over the Highlands of Scotland, May 2024
 
 &lt;/figcaption>
 &lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>

&lt;script type="application/ld+json">
 [
 {
 "@context": "https://schema.org/",
 "@type": "ImageObject",
 "contentUrl": "/post/2025/01/happy-new-year-2025/ScotlandAurora.jpg",
 "license": "https://jonsaville.com/credits/",
 "acquireLicensePage": "https://jonsaville.com/credits/",
 "creditText": "The personal website of Jon Saville",
 "creator": {
 "@type": "Person",
 "name": "Jon Saville"
 },
 "copyrightNotice": "Copyright Jon Saville"
 }
 ] 
&lt;/script></description></item><item><title>Hosting history</title><link>https://jonsaville.com/post/2024/05/hosting-history/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonsaville.com/post/2024/05/hosting-history/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an old joke that tech peoples&amp;rsquo; personal sites mostly have a detailed post about how it&amp;rsquo;s hosted and little else. So here we are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s over 20 years since I first started hosting a website at a domain I controlled on a server I also controlled. Then, as now, it was less about the content (obviously) than the process - learning what worked and what didn&amp;rsquo;t - and inching towards some platonic ideal of efficiency and automation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hosting both web and email was challenging but fun in those early days, especially for someone like me who enjoys getting down to the bare metal. Like most things it has become cheaper and easier over time, but also more beholden to a few giant corporations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy New Year 2024</title><link>https://jonsaville.com/post/2024/01/happy-new-year-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonsaville.com/post/2024/01/happy-new-year-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay so this is a cheat - I&amp;rsquo;m writing this in May 2024, in the Highlands of Scotland, in glorious sunshine, shortly after the amazing aurora display and shortly before my fiftieth birthday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last 18 months have been hectic to say the least, but a post on Mastodon reminded me not to worry too much about this site.&lt;/p>











		
		

		
			
			
		

		
			&lt;blockquote class="toot-blockquote" cite="https://front-end.social@mia/status/112056878975842288">
				&lt;div class="toot-header">
					&lt;a class="toot-profile" href="https://front-end.social/@mia" target='_blank' rel="noopener">
						&lt;img
							src="https://cdn.masto.host/frontendsocial/accounts/avatars/109/287/575/127/245/522/original/0b4a5e7e3baf5a07.jpeg"
							alt="Mastodon avatar for @mia@front-end.social"
							loading="lazy"
						/>
					&lt;/a>
					&lt;div class="toot-author">
						&lt;a class="toot-author-name" href="https://front-end.social/@mia" target='_blank' rel="noopener">Mia (web luddite)&lt;/a>
						&lt;a class="toot-author-handle" href="https://front-end.social/@mia" target='_blank' rel="noopener">@mia@front-end.social&lt;/a>
					&lt;/div>
				&lt;/div>
				&lt;p>You&amp;#39;re allowed to post on your blog once every decade, and you don&amp;#39;t even need to apologize for it. That&amp;#39;s also part of having your own space. &lt;/p>&lt;p>Personal sites aren&amp;#39;t a competition, and productivity doesn&amp;#39;t have to be a metric.&lt;/p>&lt;p>(note to self)&lt;/p>
				
				
				
				&lt;div class="toot-footer">
					&lt;a href="https://front-end.social/@mia/112056878975842288" class="toot-date" target='_blank' rel="noopener">10:57 PM • March 7, 2024&lt;/a>&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="pokey">(UTC)&lt;/span>
				&lt;/div>
			&lt;/blockquote>
		
	
&lt;p>I have a few posts queued so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how quickly they are published. The rest of 2024 promises to be busy as well, so in the meantime I am enjoying this beautiful part of the world with Lindsey, drinking a little whisky, and not worrying too much about the outside world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy New Year 2023</title><link>https://jonsaville.com/post/2023/01/happy-new-year-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonsaville.com/post/2023/01/happy-new-year-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well 2022 continued to be weird in lots of unhelpful ways. This seems to be the new normal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After saying &lt;a href="https://jonsaville.com/post/2022/01/happy-new-year-2022/">last year&lt;/a> that I wanted to post here more often, I managed two whole articles in 2022: a &lt;a href="https://jonsaville.com/post/2022/01/games-played-2021/">look at the games I had enjoyed playing in 2021&lt;/a>, and a &lt;a href="https://jonsaville.com/post/2022/09/sports-watches/">review of the Garmin Fenix 7S&lt;/a> sports watch. No promises for 2023&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did manage to read 11 books last year. Compared to my youth this is pathetic, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get back into it. The ongoing destruction of Twitter by an alt-right man-child has probably helped if I&amp;rsquo;m honest. Best book of the year was probably &lt;a href="http://www.nickharkaway.com/books/gnomon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gnomon&lt;/a> by Nick Harkaway. I&amp;rsquo;m also re-reading the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperion_Cantos" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hyperion Cantos&lt;/a> by Dan Simmons - some of the best SciFi ever written.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of SciFi, one of the best TV adaptations I&amp;rsquo;ve seen came to Amazon Prime - The Peripheral, from the book by William Gibson. This was a high bar to reach as Gibson is one of my favourite authors and the book is loved by his fans. The changes to plotting were fair and the cast and staging superb. Given the cliffhanger ending it&amp;rsquo;s to be hoped that a second season is rapidly commissioned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still have an account on Twitter, but &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@jonsaville" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mastodon&lt;/a> is where to find me. I like Mastodon, both in principle and practice. I hope it gains enough traction to succeed at a mass scale. Some communities have migrated wholesale (infosec being one), but others are lagging.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2023 promises to be busy and weird, again. All the best!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy New Year 2022</title><link>https://jonsaville.com/post/2022/01/happy-new-year-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonsaville.com/post/2022/01/happy-new-year-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wrote &lt;a href="https://jonsaville.com/post/2021/01/happy-new-year/">last year&lt;/a> that 2020 was a weird and difficult year, and 2021 doubled down on that. The year was very busy work-wise, but there was a relentless quality to the pandemic as Covid ebbed and flowed that ground down my enthusiasm. I&amp;rsquo;ve always tried to use social media to highlight positive news, but that approach took a battering last year, especially as politics continued to diverge from reality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s now 22 months since I travelled outside the UK - by far the longest period since university. Although air travel is not exactly sustainable, my experiences travelling for work and pleasure have been very formative, and the sudden halt with few signs of recovery has required some mental readjustment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously I didn&amp;rsquo;t post here as often as I wanted. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to improve on that in 2022, and have a very full slate this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take care of yourselves and be kind.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Credits</title><link>https://jonsaville.com/credits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonsaville.com/credits/</guid><description>&lt;p>This site is built with the static site generator &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hugo&lt;/a>, and uses a customised theme based on &lt;a href="https://github.com/lxndrblz/anatole/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anatole&lt;/a> by Alexander Bilz, itself based on &lt;a href="https://github.com/hi-caicai/farbox-theme-Anatole" target="_blank" rel="noopener">farbox-theme-Anatole&lt;/a> by Cai Cai. The paginator is based on an article by &lt;a href="https://glennmccomb.com/articles/how-to-build-custom-hugo-pagination/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Glenn McComb&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fonts are &lt;a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Roboto" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Roboto&lt;/a> by Christian Robertson and &lt;a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Open&amp;#43;Sans" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open Sans&lt;/a> by Steve Matteson, both from &lt;a href="https://fonts.google.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Fonts&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The glitch image was made with the fantastic iOS app &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/retrospecs/id887031094" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Retrospecs&lt;/a>, and the Hugo shortcode used to embed Mastodon Toots is by &lt;a href="https://www.brycewray.com/posts/2022/06/static-mastodon-toots-hugo/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bryce Wray&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After many years of being hosted on AWS S3, the site now lives on &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="copyright">Copyright&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>All content on this site is Copyright Jon Saville {{ now.Format &amp;ldquo;2006&amp;rdquo;}}. You do not have permission to take words or images and use them elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="last-build">Last build&lt;/h3>


&lt;span>2025-01-06 21:16 UTC&lt;/span></description></item><item><title>Happy New Year 2021</title><link>https://jonsaville.com/post/2021/01/happy-new-year/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonsaville.com/post/2021/01/happy-new-year/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the area of New Year resolutions, this seemed like a good opportunity to update my personal site, which has offered just a single page for the last few years. The intention is to post more updates on more subjects, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see how normal life interferes with that goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2020 was a weird and difficult year, and we are not out of the woods yet. Today also marks the completion of the UK&amp;rsquo;s withdrawal from Europe. Speaking personally, as someone who has travelled and worked across Europe, I find this sad, damaging and retrograde. Obviously those contacts can continue, but the theatre of a political divorce, not to mention the economic impact, seems ridiculous given the global issues we all face.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky to travel extensively throughout my career. This almost completely stopped in 2020 and is unlikely to return to previous levels, which has prompted me to look back over the photos taken in some of these countries. Hopefully some of these will make it onto the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The site still uses &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hugo&lt;/a>, but with a new theme. See the &lt;a href="https://jonsaville.com/credits/">credits&lt;/a> page for more details on how the site is built. There&amp;rsquo;s obviously more work to do - the mobile version is broken, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to remove external dependencies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>